## **ALEX VALLADARES**

South Plainfield, New Jersey 07080 | (201) 686-0997 | <u>Alex.valla101@gmail.com</u> https://github.com/valla101 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-valladares-833903140/

#### SUMMARY

Intellectually curious Data Analyst with experience in collecting and presenting data for the purpose of quantifying and simplifying raw data. Strengths include Python, SQL, ETL, Tableau, and Excel. Possesses skills to work on back end and front end of full stack applications. Currently responsible for maintaining equipment and coordinating work with three Port Authority of NY/NJ facilities.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming & Databases: Python, SQL, Tableau, JavaScript (HTML/CSS), VBA, ETL

PLC Programming: Schneider Electric Unity Pro, Vijeo Citect (SCADA Software)

Misc: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access

### **PROJECTS**

# Vacation Planner using Google API | <a href="https://github.com/valla101/python\_api\_challenge">https://github.com/valla101/python\_api\_challenge</a>

• Generated a Map of Hotels based on a client's Ideal Weather Conditions using Google Maps. Gathered Data from CitiPi, Open Weather API, Google Maps API.

Technologies used: Python, Google Maps API, OpenWeather API, Pandas, JSON Requests, Numpy, CitiPi.

## NBA Awards Predictor | https://github.com/RU-DataScience-Group5/BasketballML

Full Stack Application that references player statistics since 1980. A Machine Learning Model was developed to
determine this season's Most Valuable Player and Rookie of The Year. Contributed with developing Flask
routes, front end styling and user interaction.

Technologies used: Python, Pandas, PostgreSQL, Flask, SciKit Learn, JavaScript, AWS Database.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Rutgers University**

Coding Bootcamp - Data Science Certificate

**February 2020 – August 2020** 

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning

### **New Jersey Institute of Technology**

September 2012 – December 2016

B.S. Mechanical Engineering

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Kapsch TrafficCom - Secaucus, NJ

April 2019 - Present

### Field Service Technician

- Troubleshooting & Maintaining on low voltage (DC) devices and PLC Electrical Panels
- HMI configuration with Vijeo Citect for SCADA system
- PLC Software Configuration using Schneider Electric's Unity Pro
- Data Communications Analysis
- On-site commissioning of SCADA System at World Trade Center

### All American Poly – Piscataway, NJ

**April 2018 – March 2019** 

### Maintenance Engineer

- Document and organize inventory system (Fiix) for all assets and spare parts including motors, belts, bearings, and motor drives
- Use lean methodology to improve the longevity of parts and reduce scrap
- Develop Return on Investment for any potential new equipment
- Troubleshoot with PLC's